THOMAS YAW ASANTE

thomasyaw2000@gmail.com +233249627687

OBJECTIVE

Experienced Computer Assistant who has extensive experience with customer support and backend technical work. Adept at software and hardware upgrades customer training and logging network troubleshooting issues. Specializes in operating system support and application development.

WORK EXPERIENCE

09/2015 - 09/2018, MIS , Ayawaso north municipal assembly (nabco personnel agric department)

- Develop and Maintain Organization Network and Databases
- Ensure Stable Operation of Organization's Network and Databases
- Implement Software and Security Updates
- Troubleshoot and Fix IT Issues
- Manage IT Staff

09/2015 - 09/2018, IT Engineer, Engineering and Development consultant Ghana

- Responsible for logging all network and workstation issues that occurred each day.
- Install hardware and software systems
- Maintain and repair IT equipment
- Troubleshoot a variety of computer issues
- Set up computer security measures
- Configure computer networks
- Offer technical support on-site or via phone or email
- Maintain record of daily data communication transactions, problems and remedial actions taken
- Control of architecture drawings in office and sites
- Resolved any virus and malware issues and managed Windows and Linux servers.

05/2012 - 09/2015, IT support officer Omni-IT Consulting / GKLGhana Ltd

- Installation and maintenance of all systems within a client's digital environment.
- Producing documentation on operational, system and user procedures & guidelines
- Providing advice on selection and purchase of IT equipment.
- Maintaining maximum availability of supported services for users
- Performing routine audits of systems and software.
- Performing backups.
- Applying operating system updates, patches, and configuration changes.
- Ensuring that support calls are logged and handled effectively and efficiently.
- Responsible for disaster recovery, closing security loopholes and access levels.
- Ensure adequate antivirus protection & solutions are maintained and updated
- Adding, removing, or updating user account information, resetting passwords.etc.
- Installing and configuring new hardware and software
- Ensuring that the network infrastructure is up and running.
- Setting up computer security measures
- Offering technical support onsite and via phone or email

05/2009 - 09/2011, IT support Engineer Ministry of Road and Highways

- Helped migrate services from Windows Server 2003 to Windows Server 2008 R2.
- Managed SQL Server 2005 & Exchange 2007, and over 300 user accounts in Active Directory.
- Managed and Administered Windows XP and Windows 7 workstations and laptops.
- Supported and maintained servers and backups.
- Supported Microsoft Office 2007/2010.
- Shared knowledge with new recruits.
- Installing hardware and software systems
- Maintained various hardware and software and worked on the improvement of data security.
- Troubleshooting a variety of computer issues
- Configured VPN, backed up and restored data, and managed relevant correspondence.

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

2021 GHANA TECH LAB

Certificate in Data Science Training

2007-2009, IPMC COLLEGE OF TECHNOLOGY GHANA

Diploma in Engineer 2010, Microsoft Certified System Engineer (MCSE) 2003

2003 - 2006, APOSTLES REVELATION SOCIETY TECHNICAL INSTITUTE

Diploma Certificate in auto mobile engineering

INTERESTS

• Music, Football, Painting

REFERENCES

Mr Alan Archampong
Administrator
EDC Engineering and Development
Tel 0547330497
aarchampong@gmail.com

Mr. Victor Amamu
The Director of Rsim - research statistics & information management
P.O. Box M 57. Accra, Ghana
+233 302 681668
Amamu.victor@mrt.gov.gh